Guide to the Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 5. Constituent Services Files, 1976-2007 TJU.2010.01.05
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 5. Constituent Services Files
1976-2007
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Specter, Arlen
TJU.2010.01.05
454.59 Linear Feet
The Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 5. Constituent Services Files document Specter's efforts of behalf on his constituents. Specter served as U.S. Senator from 1981 to 2011, making him the longest-tenured Pennsylvanian senator. The group contains correspondence, bulk mailings, grant applications, grant award letters, memos, newsclips and background information files.
Custodial History
Material was transferred to the care of Philadelphia University in 2010-2011 from the Federal Records Storage Facility in Suitland, Maryland, as well as the Senator's Washington, D.C. and Pennsylvania offices. The physical material was transferred to the University of Pittsburgh in 2014, with the exception of selected photographic and memorabilia items that remain at the Arlen Specter Center's Roxboro House for display. In 2016, Philadelphia University merged with Thomas Jefferson University, and is now known as Thomas Jefferson University- East Falls campus.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Arlen Specter to Philadelphia University in 2010. Philadelphia University and the University of Pittsburgh entered into a partnership to jointly manage the collection in 2013.
Biography
Born in Wichita, Kansas, on February 12, 1930, Arlen Specter came to Pennsylvania to attend the University of Pennsylvania. He married Joan Levy in 1953, and graduated from Yale Law School in 1956. He became assistant district attorney in Philadelphia in 1959. In 1962, Specter was recommended to serve on the Warren Commission, assembled to investigate the assassination of President John F. Kennedy. As part of the Commission, he was responsible for co-authoring the proposal of the "single bullet theory," determining that one bullet struck both President Kennedy and Texas Governor John Connally. Specter ran for Philadelphia district attorney in 1965, switching his Party membership to Republican in order to unseat the incumbent Democrat. He was successful, and served as district attorney from 1966 to 1974.
After an initial failed run for Senator and then for Governor of Pennsylvania, Specter was elected to the U.S. Senate in 1980. He would stay in this position from 1981 to 2011, making him the longest-tenured senator in Pennsylvania's history. During this time, he was a member of a number of Committees: Judiciary (1981-2011; Chair, 2007-2007), Appropriations (1981-2011), Veterans Affairs (1981-2011; Chair, 1997-2001 and 2003-2005), Select Intelligence (1985-1991; 1995-1997; Chair, 1995-1997), Special Aging (1991-1995; 2007-2011), Governmental Affairs (1997-2001; 2003-2005), and Environment and Public Works (2001-2003; 2009-2011).
Though elected as a Republican, Specter was a moderate on many issues, including healthcare reform, immigration, and abortion. He would often cross party lines, such as in voting against the confirmation of President Ronald Reagan's nominee Judge Robert Bork to the Supreme Court in 1987. Specter would again come into the spotlight during a Supreme Court nomination process in 1991, for his cross-examination of Professor Anita Hill regarding her allegations against nominee Clarence Thomas. In 1999, he would vote against the charges brought against President Bill Clinton, giving an answer of "not proven" to reflect his belief that Clinton had not received a fair trial.
As Senator, Specter championed a number of causes and influenced many legislative areas. He was frequently a member of Congressional Delegation trips, particularly to the Middle East, where he would speak out on the cause of freedom from religious persecution and the importance of strong diplomatic relations. He was also a proponent of funding for medical research, including the use of stem cells. He advocated for strict crime laws, particularly for career criminals. His focus on benefitting Pennsylvania could be seen through the pursuit of grant funding opportunities and his attempt to prevent the closure of the Philadelphia Naval Shipyard in the 1990s.
With the worsening of Congressional partisanship in the late 2000s, Specter found himself frequently voting with his Democratic peers. After being one of only three handful of Republicans to vote for the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act in 2009, Specter found himself increasingly marginalized within his party. In April 2009, he returned to the Democratic Party, helping to ensure the passage of the Affordable Care Act. Seeking re-election in 2010, he was defeated in the Democratic primary by Joe Sestak.
Specter's 30-year tenure in the Senate concluded in January 2011. After leaving the Senate, he partnered with Philadelphia University (now Jefferson-East Falls) to establish the Arlen Specter Center for Public Service. In the fall of 2012, Specter, who had previously beaten Hodgkin's lymphoma in 2005 while serving as Chair of the Judiciary Committee, was diagnosed with cancer. He died on October 14, 2012, aged 82.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
The Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 5. Constituent Services Files comprises 365 boxes of material reflecting Specter's efforts of behalf on his constituents. These files include constituent mail, information about the application for and the awarding of federal grants, and documentation of specific actions taken in Pennsylvania. The group contains correspondence, bulk mailings, grant applications, grant award letters, memos, newsclips and background information files.
Arrangement
Group 5 is arranged into three series reflecting Specter's efforts of behalf on his constituents:
Series I. Constituent Correspondence, 1978-2006
Series II. Grants, 1981-2007
Series III. Local Services, 1976-2002
Related Material
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 1. Pre-Senatorial Career Files, 1953-1980, TJU.2010.01.01
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 2. Legislative Files, 1965-2011, TJU.2010.01.02
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 3. Personal, Political and Official Files, 1944-2010, TJU.2010.01.03
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 4. Office Administration Files, 1962-2010, TJU.2010.01.04
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files, 1972-2010, TJU.2010.01.06
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 7. Campaign Files, 1976-2004, TJU.2010.01.07
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 8. Awards and Memorabilia, 1957-2010, TJU.2010.01.08
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 9. Photographs, 1930-2010, TJU.2010.01.09
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 10. Electronic Records, 1980-2010, TJU.2010.01.10
Allegheny County (Pa.); Politicians; Correspondence; Constituents; Grants; Pennsylvania; Philadelphia (Pa.); Pittsburgh (Pa.); Wilkes-Barre (Pa.); Scranton (Pa.); Erie (Pa.); Allentown (Pa.); Lancaster (Pa.); United States. Congress. Senate; United States. Congress; Specter, Arlen
- Constituent Correspondence, 1978-2006; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Constituent Correspondence contains letters and bulk mailings sent to Senator Specter's office on a variety of issues. The majority of the mail dates from prior to 1990. Issues covered include agriculture, judicial matters, healthcare, immigration, abortion, foreign affairs, and many others. This series has been only minimally processed, and is arranged chronologically.
  - No response needed, 1978 and 1985 (Box 714)
  - CMS files, January-February 1981 (Box 715)
  - CMS files, January-March 1981 (Box 716)
  - CMS files, March 1981 (Box 717)
  - CMS files, March 1981 (Box 718)
  - CMS files, March-April 1981 (Box 719)
  - CMS files, March-April 1981 (Box 720)
  - CMS files, March-April 1981 (Box 721)
  - CMS files, March-April 1981 (Box 722)
  - CMS files, March-April 1981 (Box 723)
  - CMS files, March-April 1981 (Box 724)
  - CMS files, March-May 1981 (Box 725)
  - CMS files, April 1981 (Box 726)
  - CMS files, April 1981 (Box 727)
  - CMS files, April-May 1981 (Box 728)
  - CMS files, April-May 1981 (Box 729)
  - CMS files, April-May 1981 (Box 730)
  - CMS files, April-May 1981 (Box 731)
  - CMS files, April-May 1981 (Box 732)
  - CMS files, April-May 1981 (Box 733)
  - CMS files, April-June 1981 (Box 734)
  - CMS files, April-June 1981 (Box 735)
  - CMS files, April-July 1981 (Box 736)
  - CMS files, May 1981 (Box 737)
  - CMS files, May-June 1981 (Box 738)
  - CMS files, May-June 1981 (Box 739)
  - CMS files, June 1981 (Box 740)
  - CMS files, June 1981 (Box 741)
  - CMS files, July 1981 (Box 742)
  - CMS files, July 1981 (Box 743)
  - CMS files, July 1981 (Box 744)
  - CMS files, July-August 1981 (Box 745)
  - CMS files, July-August 1981 (Box 746)
  - CMS files, July-August 1981 (Box 747)
  - CMS files, August-September 1981 (Box 748)
  - CMS files, August-December 1981 (Box 749)
  - CMS files, September 1981 (Box 750)
  - CMS files, September 1981 (Box 751)
  - CMS files, September 1981 (Box 752)
  - CMS files, September-October 1981 (Box 753)
  - CMS files, September-October 1981 (Box 754)
  - CMS files, September-October 1981 (Box 755)
  - CMS files, October 1981 (Box 756)
  - CMS files, October 1981 (Box 757)
  - CMS files, October-November 1981 (Box 758)
  - CMS files, October-November 1981 (Box 759)
  - CMS files, October-November 1981 (Box 760)
  - CMS files, November-December 1981 (Box 761)
  - CMS files, November-December 1981 (Box 762)
  - CMS files, November-December 1981 (Box 763)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 764)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 765)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 766)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 767)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 768)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 769)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 770)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 771)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 772)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 773)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 774)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 775)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 776)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 777)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 778)
  - CMS files, 1981 (Box 779)
  - CMS responses, 1981-1999 (Box 780)
  - Data, 1981 (Box 781)
  - Data top sheets, June-August 1981 (Box 782)
  - Data top sheets, 1981 (Box 783)
  - Data top sheets, 1981 (Box 784)
  - Data top sheets, 1981 (Box 785)
  - No response needed, January-March 1981 (Box 786)
  - No response needed, April-May 1981 (Box 787)
  - No response needed, April-May 1981 (Box 788)
  - No response needed, August 1981 (Box 789)
  - No response needed, August 1981 (Box 790)
  - No response needed, 1981 (Box 791)
  - No response needed, 1981 (Box 792)
  - No response needed, 1981 (Box 793)
  - No response needed, 1981 (Box 794)
  - No response needed, 1981 (Box 795)
  - No response needed, 1981 (Box 796)
  - Weekly abstracts, February-April 1981 (Box 797)
  - Weekly abstracts, April-May 1981 (Box 798)
  - Weekly abstracts, June-July 1981 (Box 799)
  - Weekly abstracts, July 1981 (Box 800)
  - Weekly abstracts, July-August 1981 (Box 801)
  - Weekly abstracts, August 1981 (Box 802)
  - Weekly abstracts, September-October 1981 (Box 803)
  - Weekly abstracts, October-November 1981 (Box 804)
  - Weekly abstracts, November 1981 (Box 805)
  - Weekly abstracts, November-December 1981 (Box 806)
  - Weekly abstracts, December 1981 (Box 807)
  - CMS files, 1981-1982 (Box 808)
  - Data top sheets, 1981-1982 (Box 809)
  - Topics, 1981-2003 (Box 810)
  - Weekly abstracts, December 1981-January 1982 (Box 811)
  - Constituent mail, 1982 (Box 812)
  - CMS files, January-February 1982 (Box 813)
  - CMS files, January-February 1982 (Box 814)
  - CMS files, January-February 1982 (Box 815)
  - CMS files, January-February 1982 (Box 816)
  - CMS files, January-February 1982 (Box 817)
  - CMS files, January-February 1982 (Box 818)
  - CMS files, January-February 1982 (Box 819)
  - CMS files, January-March 1982 (Box 820)
  - CMS files, January-March 1982 (Box 821)
  - CMS files, January-March 1982 (Box 822)
  - CMS files, January-April 1982 (Box 823)
  - CMS files, February 1982 (Box 824)
  - CMS files, February-March 1982 (Box 825)
  - CMS files, February-March 1982 (Box 826)
  - CMS files, February-March 1982 (Box 827)
  - CMS files, February-March 1982 (Box 828)
  - CMS files, February-March 1982 (Box 829)
  - CMS files, February-March 1982 (Box 830)
  - CMS files, February-March 1982 (Box 831)
  - CMS files, February-April 1982 (Box 832)
  - CMS files, February-April 1982 (Box 833)
  - CMS files, February-April 1982 (Box 834)
  - CMS files, March 1982 (Box 835)
  - CMS files, March-April 1982 (Box 836)
  - CMS files, March-April 1982 (Box 837)
  - CMS files, March-April 1982 (Box 838)
  - CMS files, March-April 1982 (Box 839)
  - CMS files, March-April 1982 (Box 840)
  - CMS files, March-April 1982 (Box 841)
  - CMS files, March-May 1982 (Box 842)
  - CMS files, March-May 1982 (Box 843)
  - CMS files, March-May 1982 (Box 844)
  - CMS files, March-May 1982 (Box 845)
  - CMS files, March-May 1982 (Box 846)
  - CMS files, March-June 1982 (Box 847)
  - CMS files, April 1982 (Box 848)
  - CMS files, April-May 1982 (Box 849)
  - CMS files, April-May 1982 (Box 850)
  - CMS files, April-June 1982 (Box 851)
  - CMS files, April-June 1982 (Box 852)
  - CMS files, May-June 1982 (Box 853)
  - CMS files, May-June 1982 (Box 854)
  - CMS files, May-July 1982 (Box 855)
  - CMS files, May-July 1982 (Box 856)
  - CMS files, June-July 1982 (Box 857)
  - CMS files, June-July 1982 (Box 858)
  - CMS files, June-July 1982 (Box 859)
  - CMS files, June-August 1982 (Box 860)
  - CMS files, June-August 1982 (Box 861)
  - CMS files, June-August 1982 (Box 862)
  - CMS files, July-August 1982 (Box 863)
  - CMS files, July-September 1982 (Box 864)
  - CMS files, July-September 1982 (Box 865)
  - CMS files, July, August and October 1982 (Box 866)
  - CMS files, August 1982 (Box 867)
  - CMS files, August-September 1982 (Box 868)
  - CMS files, August-September 1982 (Box 869)
  - CMS files, September 1982 (Box 870)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 871)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 872)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 873)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 874)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 875)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 876)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 877)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 878)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 879)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 880)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 881)
  - CMS files, 1982 (Box 882)
  - CMS outgoing responses, January-March 1982 (Box 883)
  - Data top sheets, February-May 1982 (Box 884)
  - Data top sheets, April-June 1982 (Box 885)
  - Data top sheets, October-December 1982 (Box 886)
  - Data top sheets, 1982 (Box 887)
  - No response needed, January 1982 (Box 888)
  - No response needed, January-February 1982 (Box 889)
  - No response needed, March 1982 (Box 890)
  - No response needed, April 1982 (Box 891)
  - No response needed, May 1982 (Box 892)
  - No response needed, June-July 1982 (Box 893)
  - No response needed, July-August 1982 (Box 894)
  - No response needed, July-August 1982 (Box 895)
  - No response needed, September 1982 (Box 896)
  - No response needed, 1982 (Box 897)
  - Weekly abstracts, January 1982 (Box 898)
  - Weekly abstracts, January 1982 (Box 899)
  - Weekly abstracts, January-February 1982 (Box 900)
  - Weekly abstracts, February-March 1982 (Box 901)
  - Weekly abstracts, February-April 1982 (Box 902)
  - Weekly abstracts, March-April 1982 (Box 903)
  - Weekly abstracts, March-May 1982 (Box 904)
  - Weekly abstracts, April 1982 (Box 905)
  - Weekly abstracts, April-May 1982 (Box 906)
  - Weekly abstracts, May-June 1982 (Box 907)
  - Weekly abstracts, June-July 1982 (Box 908)
  - Weekly abstracts, July 1982 (Box 909)
  - Weekly abstracts, July-September 1982 (Box 910)
  - Weekly abstracts, July-October 1982 (Box 911)
  - Weekly abstracts, August-September 1982 (Box 912)
  - Weekly abstracts, September-October 1982 (Box 913)
  - Weekly abstracts, November-December 1982 (Box 914)
  - Weekly abstracts, December 1982 (Box 915)
  - Weekly abstracts, December 1982 (Box 916)
  - Data, 1982-1985 (Box 917)
  - Weekly history reports, July 1982-October 1983 (Box 918)
  - CMS files, 1983 (Box 919)
  - CMS files, 1983 (Box 920)
  - Weekly abstracts, February-March 1983 (Box 921)
  - CMS files, 1983-1984 (Box 922)
  - CMS files, 1983-1985 (Box 923)
  - CMS files, 1983-1989 (Box 924)
  - Data, 1983-1984 (Box 925)
  - Targeted mailings, 1983-1984 (Box 926)
  - Data, 1984 (Box 927)
  - Data, June-July 1984 (Box 928)
  - CMS files, 1984-1985 (Box 929)
  - Data, 1984-1985 (Box 930)
  - Letters and order forms, 1984-1985 (Box 931)
  - CMS files, March-June 1985 (Box 932)
  - CMS files, June-July 1985 (Box 933)
  - CMS files, July-October 1985 (Box 934)
  - CMS files, August-November 1985 (Box 935)
  - CMS files, September-October 1985 (Box 936)
  - CMS files, September-November 1985 (Box 937)
  - CMS files, October-November 1985 (Box 938)
  - CMS files, October-November 1985 (Box 939)
  - CMS files, 1985 (Box 940)
  - CMS files, 1985 (Box 941)
  - CMS files, 1985 (Box 942)
  - CMS files, 1985 (Box 943)
  - CMS files, 1985 (Box 944)
  - Data, January-November 1985 (Box 945)
  - Data, November-December 1985 (Box 946)
  - Data, November-December 1985 (Box 947)
  - Data, 1985 (Box 948)
  - Data, 1985 (Box 949)
  - Groups, February-May 1985 (Box 950)
  - Targeted mailings, 1985 (Box 951)
  - Weekly abstracts, January-March 1985 (Box 952)
  - Weekly abstracts, May-July 1985 (Box 953)
  - Weekly abstracts, August-October 1985 (Box 954)
  - Weekly abstracts, October-December 1985 (Box 955)
  - CMS files, November 1985-January 1986 (Box 956)
  - CMS files, November 1985-February 1986 (Box 957)
  - CMS files, 1985-1986 (Box 958)
  - CMS files, 1985-1986 (Box 959)
  - CMS outgoing responses, 1985-1986 (Box 960)
  - Weekly history reports, September 1985-February 1986 (Box 961)
  - Constituent mail, March 1986 (Box 962)
  - Constituent mail, May-August 1986 (Box 963)
  - CMS files, January 1986 (Box 964)
  - CMS files, January 1986 (Box 965)
  - CMS files, January-February 1986 (Box 966)
  - CMS files, January-February 1986 (Box 967)
  - CMS files, February 1986 (Box 968)
  - CMS files, February-March 1986 (Box 969)
  - CMS files, February-March 1986 (Box 970)
  - CMS files, March-April 1986 (Box 971)
  - CMS files, March-April 1986 (Box 972)
  - CMS files, March-April 1986 (Box 973)
  - CMS files, March-April 1986 (Box 974)
  - CMS files, March-June 1986 (Box 975)
  - CMS files, April-May 1986 (Box 976)
  - CMS files, April-June 1986 (Box 977)
  - CMS files, May-July 1986 (Box 978)
  - CMS files, May-July 1986 (Box 979)
  - CMS files, May-July 1986 (Box 980)
  - CMS files, May-August 1986 (Box 981)
  - CMS files, July-August 1986 (Box 982)
  - CMS files, July-September 1986 (Box 983)
  - CMS files, July-October 1986 (Box 984)
  - CMS files, August 1986 (Box 985)
  - CMS files, August-September 1986 (Box 986)
  - CMS files, August-September 1986 (Box 987)
  - CMS files, August-September 1986 (Box 988)
  - CMS files, September-October 1986 (Box 989)
  - CMS files, September-October 1986 (Box 990)
  - CMS files, 1986 (Box 991)
  - CMS files, 1986 (Box 992)
  - CMS files, 1986 (Box 993)
  - CMS files, 1986 (Box 994)
  - CMS files, 1986 (Box 995)
  - CMS responses, 1986-1997 (Box 996)
  - Data, January-March 1986 (Box 997)
  - Data, January-May 1986 (Box 998)
  - Data, January-November 1986 (Box 999)
  - Weekly abstracts, January-March 1986 (Box 1000)
  - CMS files, May-June 1986, June 1987 (Box 1001)
  - CMS files, December 1986-February 1987 (Box 1002)
  - CMS files, December 1986-February 1987 (Box 1003)
  - CMS files, Allentown office, 1986-1990 (Box 1004)
  - CMS responses, 1986-1987 (Box 1005)
  - Constituent mail, January-March 1987 (Box 1006)
  - Constituent mail, April 1987 (Box 1007)
  - Constituent mail, May 1987 (Box 1008)
  - CMS files, January-February 1987 (Box 1009)
  - CMS files, February-April 1987 (Box 1010)
  - CMS files, March-April 1987 (Box 1011)
  - CMS files, March-April 1987 (Box 1012)
  - CMS files, March-May 1987 (Box 1013)
  - CMS files, April-May 1987 (Box 1014)
  - CMS files, April-May 1987 (Box 1015)
  - CMS files, April-June 1987 (Box 1016)
  - CMS files, April-June 1987 (Box 1017)
  - CMS files, May-June 1987 (Box 1018)
  - CMS files, June 1987 (Box 1019)
  - CMS files, June-July 1987 (Box 1020)
  - Groups, February-March 1987 (Box 1021)
  - Constituent mail, Hispanic communities and Philadelphia community development, 1989-1992 (Box 1022)
  - Constituent mail, 1991-1992 (Box 1023)
  - Constituent mail, Allentown office, 1991-1992 (Box 1024)
  - Constituent mail, Medicare/health issues, 1991-2001 (Box 1025)
  - Response letters, 1992 (Box 1026)
  - Constituent mail, 1992-1994 (Box 1027)
  - Constituent mail, 1993 (Box 1028)
  - Constituent mail, November 1993-December 1994 (Box 1029)
  - Constituent mail, 1994-1995 (Box 1030)
  - Constituent mail, 1994-1999 (Box 1031)
  - Constituent mail, 1994-2001 (Box 1032)
  - Buck letters, 1994-2005 (Box 1033)
  - Constituent mail, 1995-1997 (Box 1034)
  - CMS files, 1999-2000 (Box 1035)
  - Constituent mail, Defense and immigration issues, 2000 (Box 1036)
  - Constituent mail, Health issues, 2000 (Box 1037)
  - Constituent mail, Foreign affairs/healthcare/legislative issues, 2000-2001 (Box 1038)
  - Constituent mail, Health and general issues, 2000-2001 (Box 1039)
  - CMS files, January-April 2001 (Box 1040)
  - Constituent mail, Health and Judiciary issues, 2001 (Box 1041)
  - Constituent mail, Legislative issues, 2001 (Box 1042)
  - Constituent mail, 2005-2006 (Box 1043)
- Grants, 1981-2007; II.
  Grants contains applications and awards for federal grants allocated to Pennsylvania companies and projects. This series is arranged chronologically.
  - 1981 (Box 1044)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 1045)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 1046)
  - 1982 (Box 1047)
  - 1982 (Box 1048)
  - 1982 (Box 1049)
  - 1982 (Box 1050)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 1051)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 1052)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 1053)
  - 1990-1993 (Box 1054)
  - 1990-1993 (Box 1055)
  - 1990-1993 (Box 1056)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 1057)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 1058)
  - 1994-1996 (Box 1059)
  - 1994-1996 (Box 1060)
  - 1994-1999 (Box 1061)
  - 1994-1999 (Box 1062)
  - 1998-2000 (Box 1063)
  - 1998-2005 (Box 1064)
  - 2002-2005 (Box 1065)
  - 2002-2005 (Box 1066)
  - 2002-2005 (Box 1067)
  - 2005-2007 (Box 1068)
- Local Services, 1976-2002; III.
  Local Services contains files on outreach efforts by Senator Specter in various parts of the state. This includes profiles and newsclips on Pennsylvania counties and major cities, information on local development efforts, and background material on projects backed by the Senator. This series is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Business files, 1985-1990 (Box 1069, Folder 1-12)
  - Business files, 1990-1995 (Box 1070, Folder 1-10)
  - Companies and organizations visited, 1990 (Box 1070, Folder 11-13)
  - Companies and organizations visited, 1990 (Box 1071, Folder 1-7)
  - Constituent services, 1997-1998 (Box 1071, Folder 8-10)
  - County, Memos and newsclips, 1983 (Box 1071, Folder 11-15)
  - County, Memos and newsclips, 1983 (Box 1072, Folder 1-7)
  - County, Memos and newsclips, 1985-1991 (Box 1072, Folder 8-9)
  - County, Memos and newsclips, 1996-1998 (Box 1072, Folder 10-11)
  - County, Memos and newsclips, 1998-2000 (Box 1072, Folder 12-14)
  - County, Memos and newsclips, 1998-2000 (Box 1073, Folder 1-15)
  - County, Memos and newsclips, 2001-2002 (Box 1074, Folder 1)
  - County, Outreach, 1984-1992 (Box 1074, Folder 2-12)
  - County, Outreach, 1984-1992 (Box 1075, Folder 1-2)
  - County, Visits, 1981-1989 (Box 1075, Folder 3)
  - County, Visits, 1981-1991 (Box 1075, Folder 4-7)
  - Flood relief, 1996 (Box 1075, Folder 8)
  - New courthouse in Western Pennsylvania, 1985-1986 (Box 1075, Folder 9)
  - Philadelphia Allied Action Commission, 1976-1980 (Box 1075, Folder 10-16)
  - Philadelphia Allied Action Commission, 1976-1980 (Box 1076, Folder 1-4)